what is going on you crazy little kids
so uh today I thought I would start out
a new series on gr online player worlds
so I thought I would start teaching some
people how to um actually use the player
worlds um RC correctly since like nobody
knows how to use it and I thought i'
would teach a bunch of GS2 because
there's not many tutorials on YouTube
anymore or at all in general So today
we're just going to go over RC and I'm
probably going to make some more videos
today and post some slow for the week so
um when you're on a player world there's
a thing called remote control well so
first off I'm going to be explaining
everything as if you know absolutely
nothing because everyone I've talked to
basically knows nothing so um I'm just
going to close this so when when you're
on a player world and you get hired on a
server you know you want to learn GS2
are you going to code for them you want
to press F6 and this will bring up the
remote control the outer remote control
for Grail so um I'm just going to
quickly explain all the buttons on the
console that we have here so up at the
top left this right here it does not
work it's the player list it only works
on offline RC which is this which I'll
explain later basically all it does is
gives you a full um like list of Who's
online and you can edit their attributes
in here like that and so I'm going to
close that so right here this is really
important this is called the file
browser so when we click this so this
right here is what people will download
when they join the server in in sense
anything in levels and under these are
folders that hold things like your
images your animations for your um
player um your bodies your heads um
specific levels um uh yeah holds your
gmaps and you know all your things like
that like scripts as well weapons
scripts which I'll be talking about a
little later in the video also logs
which you can set up a way to um log
things in a database which we can
explain later that's a little too much
but yeah so right here basically is just
a quick way to um upload images and all
things you're going to need for
scripting all right so up here these
three things are pretty or four things
are pretty important this one is not
actually this is just uh some options
and you just you should ignore that for
now to be honest okay so the globe with
the flag these are called server Flags
so I'm on a server it's just Dev Prime
it's really kind of a random server or
whatnot but um yeah so they don't have
any server flags at the moment but these
are these are variables that can be
accessed by any NPC and any script
so we can store things like um if you
had a bush out here and you slashed it
like this we can have it add up and
update this this variable so um let's
just say this. bush is equal to one if
we um if we save that um I'm not
authorized to even change that but if we
had um this we can actually put this
anywhere and affect this number that's
really useful for um certain things that
we'll go over later but that's just a
quick explanation of what a server flag
is for right here is the folder
configuration this is for um if on your
server if you have custom folders so um
like a music that's custom that I've
added it's basically another folder
inside of something and you just give
yourself rights to it I'll explain that
as well so um basically this is um this
the folder configuration allows you to
add different file extensions really
that's pretty much what you're going for
such as newg map for um Grails levels St
gril it's really old they don't even use
those anymore but things like your GI
your gifs images um your sound files
gmaps and just more of the same thing
over again same with your body's head SE
Shields and swords this is what allows
players to download files when they join
the game so if you add something to the
server you want to make sure that this
will show because if it doesn't show up
in the game it's probably something
wrong with
this okay so now we're going to go over
the server option
this is pretty important because um this
is like how the server runs like things
that go on with it I don't really want
to go too in depth with this but um I'll
put some links in the description to
some tutorials on how this all works but
yeah you have like your hack detection
we have um some player settings it's
kind of hard to explain this really
quickly but um basically this is like
grail's default script settings so for
example the unstick me level um when you
say unstick me we have it go here to
this X and this Y and this is how long
it'll take those are things that are
already built into Grail and we're
trying to modify them through this also
I just put this here it's just a little
comments thing so it's just a list of
comments I'll show that later too okay
so now we're going to come to this
button right here this is called um I'm
just going to call it the goey Explorer
so what this does is allow you make
allow you to make really quick um guis
so for example if you need a window and
you want a button in it we can do this
and then what you can do is actually um
have it uh export and you can get the
code for it so yeah let's say this is
what we want and click compile compile
and we have the full code just a basic
outline of it and we can take it from
there I actually do this quite a bit
even though a lot of people say not to
do this like before you judge me for
using this it's you should probably
learn how to code it first I know how to
code um systems for this but I I'd
rather just quickly do this because it's
a waste of time so yeah that's just a
quick overview but you can do a lot of
things in here I'll have specific
tutorials on these if you'd like just
comment that in all right so next what
we're going to do is talk about these
three probably most important things in
the whole thing so when you're coding in
grail online classic or player worlds or
ier or any server like that um it's
based on two different things really
well three is so you have a weapon which
is like this so what right here the
weapon is attached to the player so I've
created a weapon
so basically weapons are systems
movement scripts things that would
affect the player and mostly only the
player that's what you want to keep it
like towards you know these things are
like items or Huds or guis or messages
or systems you know things that you
would want the player to have
specifically you can affect things
serers side with these as well but you
want to keep it mainly to things that
would actually be a weapon okay so
there's also these things called classes
and right here NPCs so we're just going
to ignore this for now but an so it's
one of these guys it's a non-playing
character and we can modify him through
um script you know what an NPC is which
is right here non-playing character and
now what a class is is um it's an NPC
basically that we can access so we can
make an NPC script and we can access it
we can make a class like this and then
we can access it through an NPC so there
won't be say now let's say we have three
NPCs but we want this code to be on all
of them but we don't want to just keep
attaching it we can actually just join
each individual NPC through like a few
lines of code that connect to this
script right here and we can use it on
anything and when we edit this it'll
update in all three of them instead of
specifically going into each MPC and
fixing the script one by one so that
makes these classes very useful same
with weapons you can actually attach
these to weapon scripts so for example
if you have a inventory system and you
want something to drop it will create a
class which is an NPC of the item and
when we touch it we can take that class
delete it and add the weapon that that
class had on it back to the player it's
kind of hard to explain but we can go
over it later okay and so now these are
what we'd call a database MPC these are
what kind of control the game these are
serers side NPCs for example on dev
Prime what we have it doing at the
moment is when the player joins the game
we have it add these specific weapons
that are like um the HUD here which is
cough stolen but um but yeah so like the
inventory system I'm working on we have
this automatically download to the
player so for example yeah you know you
can have your things here um yeah so I
have some weapons here and it'll
automatically download to the player and
you can set these NPCs to do anything
pretty much anything serers side so
that's about it for um the basic
overview of um how how online um servers
work with graille so the next couple
videos I'll be teaching actual code I
know you probably want to learn it so
thanks for watching let's get right into
it
[Music]
n